"2065年12月13日 錄下夢境"
Every night, the same dream.
每天晚上 同樣的夢境
The same strange planet.
同樣奇怪的星球
But why?
但是為什麼呢？
What are they trying to tell me?
它們想告訴我什麼？
It's been thirty-four years since they arrived on this planet.
它們來到這個星球34年了
And now the days passes, the survivors
被逼住在堡壘城市的倖存者
forced to live in barrier Cities, do not live in fear.
沒有一天不是生活在恐懼中
I have vowed to end that fear.
我發誓要解除這恐懼
I believe my dreams hold the key.
我相信我的夢就是鑰匙
The question is,
問題是
will I be in time to save the Earth?
我來得及拯救地球嗎？
"舊紐約市"
Where are you?
你在哪兒？
This is a restricted area.
這裡是禁區
Do not move!
別動
What is she doing here, captain?
她在這兒幹嘛
I don't know, but we are getting her out.
不知道 我們得帶她離開這
You're coming with us.
你得跟我們走
Behind you!
小心後面
Hold it right there!
站住
Damn it! Let's move, people.
該死 快走吧
Two, coming through the wall.
有兩隻從牆裡穿過來了
Hold your fire. Those tanks are flammable!
停火 那些桶是易燃物
Ryan, Neil, let's go.
萊恩 尼爾 我們走
Just what the hell do you think you are doing?
你在幹什麼？
There is a life-form in here.
這裡有一個生物
- There hasn't been life here in years. - Well, there is now!
- 早就沒有了 - 現在有了
Life-form or not, I'm taking you in.
不管有沒有 我都要帶你走
Fine, Arrest me.
你就逮捕我啊
But I'm not leaving without that life-form.
沒有這生物我不會離開
Gonna be one of those days.
今天很倒楣啊
Captain, transport is not going to wait for us much longer.
隊長 運輸機是不會等我們的
I understand that.
我知道
It's in bad shape.
它的狀況很糟
Please. Tell me we're not risking our necks for this plant.
拜託 我們不是為了這爛植物在冒生命危險
I wouldn't even call it a plant. It's a weed.
真的都不算是植物 是雜草
I wouldn't even call it a weed.
我看連雜草都不算
I need a minute to extract it.
等我一分鐘去萃取它
Miss, that's a minute we do not have.
我們連一分鐘都沒有
I'm afraid he's right about that, ma'am.
我恐怕他說得沒錯
Phantoms! We have incoming.
有幽怪來襲
Captain, we need to get outta here.
隊長 我們得快走
Understood, sergeant.
知道了 中士
- Could you hurry please, miss? - Done.
- 拜託你快點 - 好了
- Captain. - Yes Neil.
- 隊長 - 什麼事 尼爾？
Just so you know, I agree with the "let's get out of here" thing.
我覺得咱們應該趕快離開
Duly noted.
知道了
Can I have this please? Thank you.
請把那給我好嗎？謝謝
- We're surrounded. - No Shit!
- 我們被包圍了 - 廢話
All right, everybody. Just relax.
大夥兒別緊張
Captain, we got to get to higher ground.
我們得往高處逃
Everyone, up top.
大夥兒快走 往上走
Go! Go! Go!
快走… 快
- Transport, requesting immediate evac. - Affirmative.
- 請求立刻撤退 - 收到
Up here!
在上面
Captain!
隊長
- They're right behind you! - Captain, come on!
- 他們就在你後面 - 隊長 快來呀
I've got you!
我抓到你了
- You okay? - Yeah.
- 你沒事吧？- 沒事
All right, everybody. Here they come.
好了 大夥兒 它們來了
You okay?
你沒事吧？
You're gonna be all right.
你不會有事的
Can you give me one good reason why I shouldn't arrest you?
你可說說看我為什麼不該逮捕你？
I am Dr. Aki Ross. I have clearance to be here.
我是阿琪羅絲博士 我有到此的許可證
Not unlimited clearance. And not without authorization.
不是無限制的許可 沒有授權
Captain, I don't have time for this.
我沒時間跟你爭
Do you realize you've just risked the lives of my squad and me?
你明白我們在為你冒險嗎？
Look. I don't want to talk about it.
我不想再多說
The fact of the matter is, it was worth the lives of you and your men.
事實是這值得你跟你的弟兄冒險
You and your men?
什麼弟兄？
- She thinks you are a man. - I think she's an idiot!
- 她以為你是男人 - 她是個笨蛋
- I know you are not a man. - I think you are an idiot too.
- 我知道你不是男人 - 你也是笨蛋
Very funny.
真是好笑
Well, I do wanna talk about it.
而我卻想說一說
Did it ever occur to you that maybe we wouldn't volunteer to risk our lives...
你有沒有想過我們若有選擇…
had we been given a choice?
是否會志願送死？
Well, nobody asked you to save me.
沒有人叫你們救我
I don't believe this. You have not changed a bit.
真不敢相信 你一點也沒變
Gray?
葛雷？
Yeah, nice to see you too!
是啊 很高興再見到你
"42號堡壘 城市：紐約市"
- Welcome back, captain. - We're clean.
- 歡迎歸隊 隊長 - 我們沒有被感染
Let's make sure of that, shall we?
我們最好確定一下
I hate getting scanned.
我最討厭接受掃描
Sir, these scanners are probably worse for us than the phantoms.
這掃描對我們來說比幽怪更糟
There's no probable about it, captain.
隊長 有人杯疑
These machines are suspected of causing sterility.
這玩意會造成不孕症
And I wanna have a little Neil junior to call me daddy someday.
我以後還想要個小尼爾叫我爸
- That's a spooky thought. - Why are you always busting my chops?
- 太恐怖了吧 - 你幹嘛老找我碴？
People, let's just do this thing, all right?
廢話少說 照做好嗎？
Yes, sir.
是 長官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
- 是 長官 - 是 長官
Okay, next.
好了 下一個
Looks like you've gained some weight.
你變胖了
It's called upper-body strength, Neil. Get a girlfriend.
這叫上肢力量 尼爾 找個女朋友吧
I'm working on it.
我正在努力了
You know my security rating allows me to bypass this.
我的保安級別給了我豁免權
Not today, it doesn't.
今天可不行
- Something's not right. - About this mission?
- 有點不對勁 - 這項任務？
- Or that woman? - Both.
- 還是那女的？- 都是
Next.
下一個
- Listen, captain. I think... - I don't care what you think, doctor.
- 隊長 我想… - 我不管你怎麼想
You're getting scanned just like everybody else.
你要跟別人一樣接受掃描
- Oh shit! - Captain
- 該死 - 隊長
- They got him. - There must be a mistake.
- 他受到了感染 - 一定是搞錯了
You came in contact with a phantom, sir.
你接觸到了幽怪
Please remain calm. Administering treatment shield.
請保持冷靜 啟動治療防護罩
- What level is he? - Blue.
- 什麼程度威染？- 藍色
He will be code red in three and a half minutes.
3分半鐘後就紅色警戒
We have to treat him now.
必須立刻替他治療
I'm sorry, but that's impossible.
對不起 這是不可能的
- We'll transfer him to the treatment center. - There's no time for that.
- 我們要把他轉到治療中心 - 來不及了
Get him to the table.
把他抬上手術臺
Hang in there captain.
你要挺住 隊長
Locating pathogens.
搜尋病原體
Jesus! Look at that thing.
天啊 你們看
- How much more time? - Not enough.
- 還有多少時間？- 不多了
When he reaches code red,
一旦達到紅色警戒
the treatment shield won't be able to hold the alien particles.
這個罩子就無法控制病毒
Engaging bio-etheric laser.
啟動生化鐳射槍
- What's going on? - Where did it go?
- 怎麼回事？- 它跑哪兒去了？
What the hell is going on?
怎麼了？
We've lost contact.
我們失去它的蹤影
Infestation is moving deeper.
病毒往深處移動
- Tracking... - There is no time.
- 追蹤 - 沒時間了
- Tracking. - There is no time!
- 快追蹤 - 來不及了
You're gonna lose him.
他會死的
His treatment shield is failing
防護罩失效了
Found it!
找到了
Come on.
快呀
It's all right.
沒事了
Don't worry.
不用擔心
You'll be back to normal in no time.
你很快就會恢復的
Doctor, we need to scan you for infestation.
博士 你必須接受掃描看是否有感染
That won't be necessary.
這沒有必要
I'll take responsibility.
我願意負責
Hey, doc.
博士
Thanks for saving him.
謝謝你救了他
- Are you all right? - Yeah, but the military has impounded my ship.
- 你沒事吧？- 沒事 軍方扣留我的船
What's with her?
她是怎麼回事？
What's with her and the captain?
她跟隊長是怎麼回事？
What's with her and that stupid plant?
她跟那根爛草是怎麼回事？
What?
幹嘛？
Forward me the phantom data and everything we've got of the five spirits collected so far.
把所有搜集到的五個靈魂的資料給我
Yes, doctor.
是 博士
Spirits? I thought we weren't supposed to use the S word.
靈魂？我以為我們不該用靈魂一詞
Don't get smart with me.
別跟我耍嘴皮子
Now let's see if that plant does the trick.
我們看看那根植物有沒有用
"萃取植物能量波"
"比對能量波"
It's a match. We've found it.
完全符合 我們找到了
Yes,
太好了
the sixth spirit.
第六個靈魂
Your little scene today broke nearly every protocol.
你今天幾乎打破了每一個協議
How long do you think this would have survived outside the barrier?
你認為這根草在外還能活多久？
Aki, you know there are elements in the Council and military
你可知那些議會和軍方有些份子
just waiting for an excuse to shut us down.
都等著要關閉我們
Look. Twenty years ago, who discovered this energy in the phantoms?
聽著 誰在20年前找到幽怪的能量波？
You.
是你
And who proved the same energy source existed in humans and every life form?
誰證明每種生物都有這能量？
You.
是你
You made it possible to harness that energy
你使人能夠控制這種能量
for OVO-packs, scanners, even the barrier.
把它用在生化電池 掃描機和堡壘城上
The Council knows that.
議會很清楚
They trust you, Doctor. We're so close to proving it...
他們相信你 我們就快能證明…
We still need this part and this one here.
我們仍然需要這部分 這一次在這裡
Exactly! Two more pieces and we've solved the puzzle.
沒錯 只缺兩個就能解開謎底
We need to be free to find those pieces.
我們必須找到它們
I want to show you something, Aki.
我給你看樣東西
- What is this? - Read.
- 這是什麼？- 讀一讀
All life is born of Gaia and each life has a spirit.
所有生命都來自蓋亞而每個生命都有靈魂
Each new spirit is housed in a physical body.
每個新靈魂都住在一個肉體內
- Doctor! - Go on.
- 博士 - 讀下去
Through their experiences on Earth, each spirit matures and grows.
依據他們在地球上的經驗每個靈魂不斷成長
When the physical body dies,
當肉體老死後
the mature spirit, enriched by its life on Earth returns to Gaia.
經過生命洗禮的成熟靈魂
Bringing with it the experiences,
將帶著這些經驗
enabling Gaia to live and grow.
回歸于蓋亞讓蓋亞存活並成長
It's my old diary.
這是我的舊日記
I wrote that fourty-three years ago when I was the age you are now.
43年前我還像你這個年紀的時候寫的
Dr. Sid!
席德博士
Remember what happened to Gallileo?
還記得伽利略的下場嗎？
They threw him in jail
他被關迸牢獄
because he said the Earth was not the center of the universe.
因為他說地球不是宇宙中心
That could happen to us.
這也可能發生在我們的身上
Our ideas are unpopular, Aki.
我們的主張並不受歡迎
If you have any notes or records, that could be used against you.
如果你有對自己不利的資料
Destroy them.
快毀掉它們
- Keep them up here. - Right.
- 記在腦子裡 - 好
And stay away from your friend, the captain.
離你朋友隊長遠一點
He saves your life, you save his life, this leads to that.
他救了你 你也救了他 別被沖昏了頭
I was young once too, you know.
我也年輕過
Doctor, there is a war going on.
博士 有一場戰爭正在進行中
No one is young anymore.
現在再沒有年輕人了
Ladies and Gentlemen of the council,
各位議員
could you please explain why?
你們能解釋為什麼嗎？
Zeus was completed a month ago.
宙斯炮一個月前完工
If we attack the meteor with this,
如果用來攻擊隕石
we will eliminate the phantoms at their source.
就能徹底消滅幽怪的巢穴
General Hein, calm down.
海恩將軍 請冷靜
At our last meeting, we voted six to two
上次我們六比二票決定
to postpone using the Zeus cannon to attack the Leonid meteor.
暫緩利用宙斯炮攻擊裡奧尼德隕石
We have reconvened today to vote on that very issue again.
這次要再投票表決
Now, I'd like to ask the director of the Bio-Etheric Center to speak.
我想請生化能量中心主任發言
- Dr. Sid, please. - Thank you.
- 席德博士 - 謝謝你
As you all know, the phantoms nest is in the Leonid meteor
大家知道幽怪巢穴是
that landed here thirty-four years ago.
34年前墜落地球的裡奧尼德隕石
What you see now,
現在所看到的
are the records of every assault on the meteor to date.
是至今每次攻擊隕石的記錄
Physical attacks have had utterly no affect.
猛烈攻擊完全無法造成損害
This scene took place three months ago during a full scale bombardment.
三個月前進行全面性轟炸行動
Now please note that the phantoms outside the meteor are indeed destroyed.
隕石外的幽怪確實被殲滅
However inside, many that were dormant come to life
但是潛伏在內的幽怪卻復蘇
and as you see overall phantom density remains the same.
而你可以看到 幽怪的密度仍然跟以前一樣
The newly risen aliens respond to the attack
當復蘇的幽怪遭到攻擊
by burrowing even deeper into the Earth.
便鑽入地球的更深層
Now this is very interesting to me, Dr. Sid.
這一點相當有趣 席德博士
Because we see the same thing during surgery
我們使用生化鐳射
when using bio-etheric lasers on phantom particles.
切除幽怪病毒時也是這祥
- Do we not? - Yes, indeed we do.
- 對不對？- 是的 沒錯
You see the injured particles escape,
受傷的病毒脫逃後
burying or digging themselves deeper into a patient's body,
會鑽入病患更深的體內
and when we increase the laser power
我們為了消滅這些在更深層的病毒
to destroy these deeper particles,
而加強鐳射量
we have had incidents resulting in further injury to a patient,
我們曾意外地 造成病患更大的傷害
and in some cases,
有時候
death.
會導致死亡
And what exactly does that mean, doctor?
這代表了什麼？
It means there's a very good chance
這代表一件事
the beam from the Zeus cannon will burn the phantoms in the meteor.
宙斯炮會消滅幽怪
Exactly. Thank you.
正是這樣 謝謝
Now, however, it also means
但是 那同時代表
that the beam energy may be too strong,
威力強大的鐳射炮
injuring the Earth.
也會傷害地球
Injure the Earth?
傷害地球？
You mean the Gaia?
你是說蓋亞？
- I mean... - You mean the spirit of the Earth.
- 我是說… - 你說的是地靈
Yes.
是的
The spirit of the Earth.
地球的靈魂
Did he just say what I think he said?
他說的是我想的那個意思嗎？
- What are you doing? - I know what I'm doing,
- 你在做什麼？- 我知道我在做什麼
and whatever you do, keep your mouth shut.
你千萬別說話
This is ridiculous.
太荒謬了
Doctor, with all due respect.
恕我直言
Did you come here just to talk about some Gaia theory?
你是來高談蓋亞論嗎？
To tell us that the planet is alive?
你說地球是活的？
That it has a spirit?
它有靈魂？
That's a fairy tale, doctor,
這是神話
and I'm sorry, but we don't have time for that.
我們沒有時間再聽這些
It is not a fairy tale, it is true.
這不是神話 這是真的
Ah, so if I point a gun at the Earth and fire,
那麼 如果我拿著槍朝地上開一槍
I'm not just making a hole on the ground, I'm killing the planet.
我不只射穿一個洞 還殺了地球
Dr. Sid, the Gaia theory has not been proven.
席德博士 蓋亞論未經證實
Even if Gaia does exist,
就算蓋亞存在
won't we still have to remove the phantoms?
我們不是也要消滅幽怪嗎？
I think if there's any chance of success,
如果有成功機會
we should take it?
就要把握
- Don't you agree? - Of course I do.
- 你不同意嗎？- 當然同意
But there is an alternative to the space cannon
但太空戰炮以外有另一個選擇
Another method?
有另一個方法？
- Yes, a means of disabling the phantoms. - Please.
- 我有一個讓幽怪癱瘓的方法 - 請說
As we know the aliens display a distinct energy pattern.
據我們所知這些外星生物散發一種能量波
Now it is a fact that two opposing bio-etheric waves
只要把兩道相反的生化波
placed one over the other will cancel each other out.
重疊在一起 就能互相抵消
It is theoretically possible to construct a wave pattern
理論上可以重建一道能量波
in direct opposition to the phantom energy.
和幽怪的能量波完全相反
- We are currently assembling - Doctor.
- 我們正在製造這種能量波 - 博士
such a wave and are nearing completion.
而且快要完成了
Members of the council
各位議員
Gathering plants and animals
搜集植物和動物
from around the world to fight the phantoms is utter nonsense.
去對抗幽怪 筒直是無稽之談
The Zeus cannon is a proven, effective weapon.
宙斯炮證實是威力強大的武器
It will kill phantoms.
它能消滅幽怪
Can we afford to wait for some crazy invention,
我們能否等待得起一些瘋狂的發明
some army of touchy-feely plants and animals,
一些憑直覺製造的動植物兵團
an invention that offers no solid evidence that it will destroy the aliens.
而卻沒有證據表明能摧毀這些外星生物？
There is evidence.
當然有證據
Our partially completed energy wave
目前半完成的能量波
has successfully stopped phantom particles
已經抑止幽怪病毒
from spreading through a terminally infected patient.
在一名受感染病患身上擴散
Doctor, do you claim to have evidence that a terminal patient has been cured.
你可有證據能證明有垂死的患者痊癒了？
Not cured. The wave is not complete.
不是痊癒 能量波尚未完成
But we've succeeded in containing the particles safely inside the patient.
但我們成功地控制了病毒的擴散
Where is the proof?
證據在哪裡？
Here.
在這裡
You may've bought us some time, Aki. But I wonder at what cost?
你也許讓我們有多一點時間 但是代價呢？
Doctor, I can't keep hiding in the background while you protect me.
我不能一直躲起來讓你維護我
I want what life I have left to mean something.
我想在餘生有所貢獻
You listen to me. When we find the seventh and eighth spirits...
你聽我說 等我們找到第七和第八個靈魂…
If we find them. What we need now is some luck.
我們需要運氣才可以找到它們
Luck has nothing to do with it.
這跟運氣無關
Faith and hard work, girl.
你要有信心和努力
Cause I'll be damned if you're going to die before me.
我絕不會讓你比我先死
The Council decided to postpone firing the Zeus cannon.
議會決定暫緩發射宙斯炮
I guess I put on a good show.
我想我的表現還不錯
Mind if I tag along?
介意我跟來嗎？
You'll probably get bored.
你會覺得無聊
So... what are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Oh, I see. You're giving me the silent treatment.
我知道了 你在跟我冷戰
I'm scanning the city for the seventh spirit.
我要在市內搜索第七個靈魂
- Hurry up, Neil. - Relax serge, I almost got it.
- 尼爾 快點 - 輕鬆點 就快好了
What do you think you're doing?
你在搞什麼鬼？
We're just gonna strand them for a while.
我要把他們困在上面一陣子
Hey, don't look at me. It was his idea.
別看我 這是他的主意
This was your idea?
這是你的主意？
We're just helping the captain out a little.
我只是想幫隊長的忙
Yeah, come on Jane, where's your sense of romance?
拜託 你的浪漫情調到哪兒去了？
You've seen how the captain looks at her.
你看到隊長看她的眼神了
It's "amore", baby.
那就是愛 寶貝
- What's going on? - It's probably just a glitch.
- 怎麼回事？- 可能只是個小故障
- Listen, Aki... - I'm still mad at you.
- 阿琪 聽著… - 我還在生你的氣
- You're mad at me? - Leaving your helmet on, not telling me who you were?
- 你生我的氣？- 你戴著頭盔不說你是誰
That doesn't seem a little childish?
難道一點也不幼稚？
I was just a little upset when you just packed up and left
你一聲不響就跑去宙斯太空站
for the Zeus station without saying a word.
讓我很生氣
Well now you know what was going on, all right? - Yeah, now I know.
- 現在你知道是怎麼回事了吧？- 我知道了
My operation had to be done in zero grav, okay?
我的任務必須在無重力狀態執行
Fine!
好吧
And how about the fact that I was sent there on a job
我去太空站出公差
and you wouldn't even see me?
而你不肯見我？
I was probably helping Dr. Sid collect spirit waves.
我大概是在搜集能量波
- Now I know. - So I'm sorry.
- 我現在知道了 - 我很遺憾
Well, me too. So we're both sorry.
我也是 我們都很遺憾
So will you tell me about them?
說來聽聽好嗎？
About what?
說什麼？
About the spirits you've collected.
你搜集的靈魂
I was infected by a phantom during an experiment.
我在一項突驗中受到幽怪感染
Normally no one could have survived.
通常沒人能活下來
How did you?
你怎麼活下來的？
Dr. Sid created a membrane around the infection,
席德博士用薄膜包住病原體
keeping me alive.
保住了我的性命
So the first spirit wave was me.
所以第一個靈魂波就是我
- The second was a fish. - A fish?
- 第二個是一條魚 - 魚？
The third was a deer I found in a wildlife-preserve outside Moscow.
第三個是我在莫斯科野生保留區找到的一隻鹿
The fourth was a bird.
第四個是一隻小鳥
Ever tried to track a sparrow from outer space?
你試過從外太空追蹤麻雀嗎？
It's no fun.
一點都不好玩
What am I saying? You probably would love that.
我在說什麼？你一定會很喜歡的
You're right. I probably would.
你說得對 我可能會
And then there was that plant I collected from Time Square.
然後就是在時代廣場的那植物
- I thought that was number six. - What?
- 那不是第六個嗎？- 什麼？
You skipped one.
你跳過一個
The fifth was a little girl dying in a hospital emergency room.
第五個是醫院急診室裡垂死的小女孩
I retrieved the sample in time, but she...
我及時採取了樣本 但是她…
I told her everything had a spirit.
我跟她說萬物都有靈魂
Dogs, cats, trees, little girls, even the Earth.
狗 貓 樹木 小女孩 就連地球也有
I told her that she wasn't dying, just returning to the Earth's spirit.
我告訴她她不是死 只是回歸到蓋亞
To Gaia.
也就是地靈
She... told me, that she was ready to die.
她跟我說她已準備好接受死亡
She said I didn't have to make up stories to make her feel better.
她說我不必編故事來安慰她
Only seven years old and ready to die.
她才七歲卻已準備好接受死亡
I'm sorry.
我很遺憾
I... have work to do. I have to find the seventh and eighth spirits.
我有工作要做 我必須找到第七和第八個靈魂
Don't... please...
別這樣
You don't believe any of this, do you?
你一點都不信 是吧？
I just... don't know, Aki.
我不知道 阿琪
Is this why you've shut me out?
所以你才避著我？
You should have told me.
你應該告訴我
I don't know how much time I have left.
我不知道我還能活多久
Who does?
誰知道呢？
I better get back to scanning.
我最好繼續我的搜尋
Captain Edwards.
愛德華隊長
You extracted a Dr. Ross from old New York, several days ago. Did you not?
幾天前你在舊紐約救回了羅絲博士？
- Yes sir. - What were your impressions of Dr. Ross?
- 是的 長官 - 你對她有什麼印象？
She seemed very capable and determined, sir.
她看來非常有決心和能力
You and the Deep Eyes are being temporarily reassigned.
你的銳眼部隊暫時被重新分派
You will guard Dr. Ross when she re-enters the wasteland.
你們要保護羅絲博士回到荒原
Understood, sir.
明白了
You don't understand yet, captain.
你還不明白 隊長
Report any aberrant behavior in Dr. Ross to the major immediately.
她若有異常行為就向少校報告
Aberrant behavior, sir?
異常行為？
The woman carries an alien infestation, captain.
她體內有外星生物感染
We don't know what it may be doing to her.
我們不知道對她有什麼影響
The alien presence could be affecting her judgment,
它可能影響她的判斷力
and may be manipulating the doctor for their very own purposes.
它們也許在操控她的行為
Is the general suggesting that Dr. Ross is a spy?
將軍認為羅絲博士是間諜？
The General is wondering why he's explaining himself to a captain.
將軍在奇怪為何他要跟一個隊長解釋
She's had prolonged exposure to phantom tissue.
她曾長期接觸幽怪細胞
If this begins to manifest itself in any way,
如果它們侵佔她的身體
Dr. Ross is to be placed under arrest,
立刻將她拘捕
and transported here for observation.
並把她帶回來接受現察
It is in fact, for her own good, captain.
這是為了她好
Of course, sir.
當然了 長官
Major, send some of our men to keep an eye on the good captain.
少校 派手下監視隊長的行動
I'm convinced that these dreams are some form of communication.
我深信這些夢境是一種交流方式
Their message still eludes me.
雖然我不瞭解
But they are coming faster now.
但它們越來越頻繁
And that can only mean one thing.
這代表一件事
The phantoms inside me are beginning to win.
我就快被體內的幽怪侵佔了
Our target is 50 klicks left, at Tucson.
目標在圖森市以西50公里
Roger.
收到
- Phantom concentration? - Not good,
- 幽怪密度？- 情況不妙
we've got big metas everywhere.
到處都有幽怪
So it's gonna be a real picnic.
這下可好玩了
Stick close to me. No heroics today, okay?
跟著我 千萬別逞強 一切照規矩來
Everything by the book.
照規矩來
By the book. Right.
照規矩來 是啊
"圖森荒原"
If we dropped energy buoys here, here and here,
先在這些地方放置能量浮標
we should be able land, acquire the target...
我們就能取得目標
and get out before the phantoms even know we were there.
趁幽怪沒察覺趕快離開
And the buoys will attract the phantoms.
浮標會把幽怪引來？
- Yeah. - For a while.
- 對 - 只是一陣子
So you're from the 307's, right?
你們是307支隊的？
Under General Hein? Ever done any wasteland recon before?
海恩將軍的部下？到荒原出過任務嗎？
It can get pretty ugly.
可能會很可怕的
Captain, rendezvous for evac at sector 6, coordinate 279.
隊長 待會撤離時到第六區 279座標會合
Roger that. Stay alert for hostiles.
收到 保持警戒
Looks like they've taken the bait.
看來它們上當了
The seventh spirit should be just beyond that line of wreckage.
第七個靈魂應該就在殘骸後面
I don't see how any living thing could survive out here.
這兒怎麼會有生物生存下來？
We'll find out soon enough.
馬上就知道了
This was the phantom cleansing mission.
這原是幽怪掃蕩任務
It was supposed to end of war.
本來應該讓戰爭結束的
My father's in here somewhere.
我父親也在這裡
All right.
好了
Let's move out, people.
我們走吧
I'll be damned.
我的天
A survivor.
一個生還者
What's it doing out here?
它在這兒幹嘛？
Hoping for life to return.
希望有重返的生命
Is that our spirit, doc?
它是第七個靈魂嗎？
No.
不是
We're closing in on the life form.
我們正接近那個生物
- Distance? - Hard to say.
- 還有多遠？- 很難說
We're very close.
我們很接近了
I don't see anything.
我什麼也沒看到
You're not gonna tell me it's him.
你不要告訴我那是他？
That's impossible
不可能
It's not the soldier. It's his OVO-pack.
不是他 是他的生化電池
How do you explain that?
不可能
The Packs power our weapons, the barrier cities...
電池提供能量給我們的武器 堡壘城市…
I mean it's just bio-etheric energy.
那只是生化能量
And to create that energy, we use living tissue.
我們用活體組織在製造能量
Single cell organism.
單細胞生物
- You're telling me his backpack is the seventh spirit? - Yes.
- 他的電池就是第七個靈魂嗎？- 沒錯
We have incoming.
幽怪來襲
- Captain, do you read me? - What? say again?
- 隊長 收到嗎？- 再說一遍？
Do you read me, captain? We have incoming.
有收到嗎？幽怪來襲
Ryan, get the soldier's pack.
萊恩 去拿那士兵的電池
I need a hand. Serge!
我需要支援 長官
- Those buoys? - Yeah.
- 那些浮標？- 是的
- They're not working. - Thank you.
- 壞了 - 謝謝你
- Are you all right? - Of course I am.
- 你沒事吧？- 當然沒事
Let's get the hell out of here!
咱們快走吧
Something's not right, this shouldn't be happening.
不應該這樣的
Something's attracting them.
有什麼東西正把它們引來
Aki!
阿琪
- They're right on us, sir. Closing in fast. - Jane, take the lead.
- 它們就快追上來了 - 簡 你打前鋒
Fire in the hole!
我要開火了
Get us out of here, Neil.
帶我們逃出去 尼爾
- Sir, I would love to, but... - Just do it!
- 我也很想 但是… - 快點
- Sir? - Ok, that's it!
- 長官？- 就這樣了
That doesn't look good, captain.
她的情況不妙
We have to get her to a hospital.
我們得送她去醫院
- You have your orders, sir. - What the hell is going on here?
- 你知道命令的 - 這是怎麼回事？
Dr. Ross is to be taken into custody, now sir!
我們必須立刻拘捕羅絲博士
Lower your weapons. That's an order.
把武器放下 這是命令
Sir, we have no choice but to relieve you of your command.
我們別無選擇只能解除你的指揮權
I won't let you do this, soldier. You're gonna have to shoot me.
我不能讓你們這麼做 你得先殺了我
Stand down, captain!
隊長 別反抗
Aki!
阿琪
Hang on everyone!
大夥兒抓緊了
That's enough! Hands where I can see them. Everyone. Now!
夠了 把手都舉起來
Deep Eyes hard to starboard!
銳眼部隊急右轉
Neil, get us back to New York. Fast.
尼爾 快飛回紐約
The Deep Eyes are returning from the wasteland, sir.
銳眼部隊從荒原回來了 長官
Apparently there was an incident.
出了一個狀況
It would seem the phantoms were attracted to Dr. Ross.
羅絲博士吸引了幽怪
The crew barely escaped with their lives.
他們差點回不來了
And sir... Captain Edwards is still in command.
但是長官… 愛德華隊長仍然有指揮權
Issue an order.
下達命令
I want Edwards and Dr. Ross placed under arrest,
我要立刻逮捕愛德華隊長和羅絲博士
all research materials pertaining to Dr. Sid's wave theory
有關席德博士能量波論的資料
are to be confiscated immediately.
全都給我沒收
That might not go over too well with the Council, sir.
議會不一定會接受
What a tragedy that would be.
那就太不幸了
This is perfect, Major.
太完美了
The good captain has opened the door for us.
隊長給了我們一個好機會
By tomorrow morning, the Council would be at our feet.
明天他們會向我下跪
Thanking us for exposing the traitors in our midst.
感謝我揪出叛徒
And imploring us to save them from the phantoms.
而且從幽怪手上救出他們
How is she, doctor?
她的狀況怎樣 博士？
- She is dying. - There must be something you can do.
- 她快死了 - 你一定還有辦法救她的
Aki is fighting with only six of the eighth spirits.
阿琪只有六個靈魂為生命搏鬥
We'll have to implant the seventh directly into her chest plate.
我必須在她胸腔植入第七個靈魂
It took a bullet. I think it might be damaged.
她中彈了 我想那胸腔可能受損了
We have to repair this panel quickly.
我們必須立刻修復這一部分
Her vital signs are dropping.
她的生命跡象在減弱
Aki is slipping away from us.
阿琪快撐不下去了
She needs a sympathetic spirit to help hold her in this world.
她需要一個友善的靈魂説明挽留她
And I can think of no spirit better suited for that task than yours, captain.
最適合的人選就是你 隊長
I don't understand. - You don't have to understand.
- 我不明白 - 你不必明白
You just be with her now.
你只要陪著她
You keep her here with us.
你挽留住她
Aki? Where are we?
阿琪 我們在哪裡？
On an alien planet.
在外星星球
How is that possible?
怎麼可能？
I'm not entirely sure.
我也不太清楚
You seem pretty calm.
你好像很冷靜
I've been having this dream every night for months.
我幾個月來每晚都有同樣的夢境
Dream?
夢境？
Well, whatever it is.
我也不知道是什麼
You're really here, aren't you?
你真的在這兒 是嗎？
What's happening to me?
我這是怎麼了？
Dr. Sid is implanting the seventh spirit directly into your body.
席德博士正在將第七個靈魂直接植入你體內
Then you're my spiritual support.
那麼你是來精神支持我的
Gray, how sweet of you.
葛雷 你對我真好
Look, I don't think you realize how serious the situation is.
我想你不知道情況有多嚴重
Something you should see here, sir.
你最好過來看看
And I am watching... what, major?
這是什麼玩意？
It seems Dr. Ross has been recording her dreams.
羅絲博士一直在記錄她的夢境
And why would I be interested in ... her dreams?
她的夢境跟我有什麼… 關係？
This is it. This is our evidence.
就是這個 這就是我們的證據
She's under the influence of the phantoms.
她受到幽怪的影響
Dr. Ross's dreams should be all the Council needs to authorize the firing of the Zeus cannon.
我要用這些來說服議會發射宙斯炮
The Council is content to hide, cowering inside this barrier
議會只顧著躲在堡壘城市
while the world dies a little more everyday.
而讓地球一天一天死去
believe they need a push in the right direction, major.
他們需要有人來推一把
Get together a group of your most trusted men.
召集你的心腹手下
What are they doing? Why are they staring at us?
他們在做什麼？它們為什麼盯著我們？
Not at us.
它們盯著的不是我們
Welcome back, captain.
歡迎回來 隊長
Is it over?
結束了嗎？
How is she, Doctor?
她怎麼樣 博士？
She's gonna be fine. But this is only temporary.
她沒事 但這只是暫時的
We'll need to find the eighth and final spirit to cure her.
一定要找到最後的第八個靈魂才能救她
Aki, can you hear me?
阿琪 你聽到嗎？
I've finished it.
我做完夢了
I know what it means.
我知道它的意思了
I know what the phantoms really are.
我知道幽怪到底是什麼了
Nobody move! You're all under arrest!
別動 你們被捕了
We have them, sir.
我們抓住他們了
Sir?
長官？
My wife and daughter.
我太太和女兒
Were killed by phantoms in the San Francisco barrier when the city was attacked.
在三藩市堡壘城市被幽怪害死了
Did I ever tell you that?
我有沒有提過？
I try to imagine what...
我試著想像她們的感受…
what that must've been like, seeing everyone around you fall over dead, for no apparent reason.
看著身邊的人無緣無故死去
And then at the end, feeling something next to you.
最後感覺有什麼在你身邊
Invisible... touching you.
無形的… 觸碰你
Reaching inside your body and...
伸入你的軀體內…
- You've lost family, haven't you? - Yes, sir.
- 你也失去了家人 對吧？- 是的
That's why I trust you.
所以我才信任你
All of you.
信任你們每個人
You know what must be done.
你們知道必須怎麼做
"堡壘主控中心"
"解除安全密碼"
"圍場被破"
Major, arrest these men.
少校 逮捕他們
- Take it easy - Stand up. Go.
- 別亂來 - 起來 走
You are relieved of your post. Don't ask questions.
你們被解職了 別多問
Reduce power to sector 31.
降低31段的防護能源
Sir, you do realize that the phantoms...
你可知道幽怪會…
What I realize, major, is that we must force the Council to take action against the enemy.
據我所知我們要逼迫議會消滅敵人
25 percent of energy pipe alpha. Redirected.
第一個電管百分之二十五的能量改向
Lowering power output to sector 31.
降低31段防護能力
Barrier breach in sector 31, General. They're coming through now.
31段防護罩失效 幽怪進來了
Oh I think we can easily handle a few phantoms in a contained space.
我們可以在密封的空間殺死幾隻幽怪
Relax, major.
別緊張 少校
When this night's over, you're going to be a hero.
明天一早你就成為英雄
- Aki, I don't think... - You were in my dream, Gray. You saw it.
- 我不… - 當時你也在 你也看到了
That's just it. I'm not sure what I saw. How can you be?
我不確定我看到的 你怎麼能確定？
Captain, please. Let her continue.
隊長 請你讓她說下去
All right. Why do you think, we've never been able
我們為什麼一直沒辦法確定
to determine a relationship between the human size phantoms
人形大小的幽怪
and the giant ones roaming the wastelands.
跟龐大幽怪的關係？
Excuse me, doc, but... what freakin relationship?
不好意思 它們能有什麼鬼關係？
I mean you got your human size phantoms and your creepy caterpillary phantoms
有人形幽怪 噁心的毛蟲幽怪
and your flying phantoms. And let's not forget my personal favorite...
會飛的幽怪 還有不要忘了我個人最喜歡的
the big fat giant phantoms...
巨大肥胖的幽怪…
- Down, boy. - He's right.
- 冷靜點 - 他說的對
If you've spend as much time in the field as we have,
要是你常跟它們周旋
you know there is no relationship. It's like a zoo out there.
就知道它們沒有關係 就像動物園一樣
Precisely. I think the giant ones are like our whales or elephants.
沒錯 大幽怪就像是我們的鯨魚或大象
But why would an invading army bring a bunch of whales and elephants along for the ride?
但是侵略部隊帶鯨魚大象來幹嘛？
Unless their ship was some kind of a crazy Noah's ark.
除非那是外星人的諾亞方舟？
We've always assumed that the meteor was intended as a form of transportation.
我們一直以為隕石是交通工具
Perhaps it wasn't.
也許它不是
The meteor is a chunk of their planet that got thrown into space...
隕石只是一塊他們炸毀星球後…
when they destroyed their world.
被扔到太空中的碎片
But how could they survive the trip across outer space on a hunk of rock?
它們怎麼能活著通過太空？
They didn't.
它們沒有存活
This is all beginning to make a creepy kind of sense.
這好像有點恐怖的道理
What do you think about all this, captain?
你覺得呢？隊長
I think that explains why we never had a chance.
我認為這就解釋了為何我們會贏不了它們
All our strategies are based on one assumption.
我們的戰略都是基於一種假設
That we were fighting alien invaders.
我們在和外星侵略者作戰
Think of the dream, Gray.
你想想夢境 葛雷
How they died.
它們是怎麼死的
Since then, all they've known is suffering.
從那之後 它們只知道痛苦
They're not an invading army.
它們不是侵略兵團
They're ghosts.
它們是鬼魂
How many phantoms?
有多少幽怪？
- More than enough to convince the Council, sir. - Excellent.
- 足夠可以說服議會的 - 太好了
- Sound an alert. Send a squad out to eliminate them. - Yes sir.
- 示警 立刻派部隊去消滅它們 - 是 長官
Alert Status: Full Deployment.
全面警戒 全體動員
Sir, I have numerous phantom contacts.
有很多幽怪來襲
- Well, of course you do. - Outside of sector 31, sir.
- 當然了 - 它們在31段以外
And moving at incredible speed.
而且行動迅速
Major, what the hell is going on here?
這到底是怎麼回事？
They are in the pipes.
它們在管道中
They're moving with the bio-etheric energy flow.
跟著生化電力一起流竄
That's impossible.
不可能
No living thing could survive in those pipes.
沒有東西可以在這些管子中存活下來
Well, we've got a big one heading this way,
一隻巨大幽怪正朝這兒沖來
meta class, sir.
是米達種的 隊長
Oh my god...
我的天
Hold your fire!
別開槍
What have I done?
我做了什麼？
Come on, Neil. We need to find a way out.
尼爾 我們得逃出去
Now you're our man, think!
你是高手 快想辦法
Captain, these walls are titanium alloy. And the bars are pulse-sonic lasers.
這是鈦合金鋼柱和鐳射光束
I mean, it's not like I can just wave a magic wand and...
我不能就這樣施展個魔法…
- Neil, I'm impressed. - That makes two of us.
- 我很佩服你 - 我也很佩服自己
"立刻前往最近的撤退區"
I think we should proceed to the nearest evacuation facility.
我們應該立刻前往最近的撤退區
- Here they come. - But the others... Dr. Sid!
- 它們來了 - 但別人呢？席德博士
Deep Eyes will take care of him. Come on!
銳眼部隊會保護他
What's happening? Why can we see them now?
怎麼回事 我們怎麼會看得見它們？
They must be carrying a residual charge from passing through the barrier.
它們身上殘留了防護罩的電力
Behind you!
小心後面
All aboard, captain.
全都上車了 隊長
We need to find my ship.
我們需要找到我的太空船
If it was towed inside the city, it would be in the military hangar.
如果它被拖到了這個城市 它一定在軍事停機棚
That's a big "If".
這個假設範圍可夠大的
Look out!
小心
- Get us out of the platform. - You got it.
- 快開到月臺 - 收到
Okay, now what?
現在呢？
- We're going through the station. - What?
- 我們要穿越車站 - 什麼？
Captain, with all due respect...
恕我直言…
- Excuse me, captain... - The Station...
- 對不起 隊長… - 車站…
We're going through it.
我們要衝過去
It's the only way.
那是唯一的出路
So I gather this will be somewhat of a rough ride.
我猜這會是一個巔簸之旅？
Doc, you've got a talent for understatement.
博士 你挺會猜測的
Hang on, everybody.
大家坐好了
Doc?
博士？
Interesting.
有意思
- Anybody hurt? - Captain!
- 有人受傷嗎？- 隊長
- Oh God! Talk to me, serge.
老天 快說話 中士
Ouch.
好疼啊
- Give me a hand, Jane. - Right.
- 幫我個忙 - 好
No, wait!
不行
We're risking further injury.
這祥會加重他的傷勢的
We need the proper tools to cut him out.
我們需要適合的工具
They're in my ship.
工具在我船上
No! No, Doc. No drugs. - Captain...
- 不 我不要打針下藥 - 隊長？
You heard the man.
你聽見他說的了
We'll find the ship and we'll be back for you.
我們會找到船然後回來找你
- I'll stay with him. - Me too.
- 我留下來陪他 - 我也是
Nobody's staying.
誰都別留下來
- Just give me a gun. - You got it.
- 給我一把槍 - 沒問題
Give him a weapon.
把槍給他
Do it!
快點
We'll be back for you, sergeant.
我們會回來救你的
You hear me?
聽到了嗎？
I hear you, captain. Now get out of here.
聽到了 隊長 快走吧
Let's move out.
我們走吧
A quad-axle ATV. This is good.
四軸越野車 太好了
It can be used to retrieve Ryan and transport him safely here.
我們可以去把萊恩救回來
However we'll need to replace these spent fuel cells.
但是要換電池
There could be some live OVO-packs in the hangar.
停機棚一定有新的電池
All right, Jane. Check the hangar.
你去停機棚
Neil, get us ready for takeoff.
尼爾 去啟動引擎
Aki and Dr. Sid prep the Quattro.
阿琪和席德博士啟動越野車
I'll go to the tower and rotate the air-tray.
我去塔臺開啟平臺
This city maybe lost, but we are not.
城市也許淪陷了 但我們不會
Let's do this thing and get the hell out of here.
我們一定會逃出去
- Gray... Be careful. - You too.
- 小心點 - 你也是
Oh, yeah.
太好了
Neil, do you read me?
尼爾 收到嗎？
Loud and clear, captain.
收到了 隊長
This baby will fly itself.
這玩意是全自動的
Flight path is set.
航道設定好了
Beginning rotation.
轉動平臺
Wow, stop, stop the air-tray. We have a problem.
停下來 有問題
I'm reading an impound tractor still attached to the prow of the ship.
太空船連著一輛被拖吊的牽引車
Can you disengage it from the cockpit?
你能從駕駛艙解開它嗎？
No, sir. Permission to go outside and detach the coupling.
請讓我到外面解開它
Do it!
快去
There's the problem.
問題在那裡
The controls are locked, naturally.
控制板被鎖住了
Jane, let me ask you something.
讓我問你一件事
You think we're gonna get outta here alive?
咱們逃得出去嗎？
I mean I'm wondering if anybody has gotten out.
不知道以前有沒有人逃出去
You think anyone's made it this far?
你覺得有人逃了這麼遠嗎？
You think this eighth spirit stuff is really gonna work against the phantoms?
這第八個靈魂真的能消滅幽怪嗎？
I mean, what if it's all a bunch of mumbo-jumbo?
也許全都是胡扯呢？
Jane, do you mind if we stop talking?
簡 拜託你別嘮叨了吧？
I'm trying to concentrate here.
讓我專心吧
What's happening down there.
下面發生了什麼事？
Nothing we can't handle.
我們都可以處理好的
- Neil, what's your status? - Almost there.
- 尼爾 怎麼樣？- 快好了
- I want you two back inside. - We're fine, sir.
- 你們快回去 - 放心
Jane is negotiating with extreme prejudice.
簡在展開強硬政策
Talk to me, Jane.
簡 快回答
No problem here, Captain.
我沒問題
Yes! Captain, we are good to go.
好了 可以出發了
No!
不
Jane, get out of there.
簡 快走
Get out of there now! Go!
快走呀 趕快走
Jane, get the hell out of there!
簡 快點離開那兒
Jane!
簡
The shield is powered and ready.
防護罩啟動了
- Where are you going? - To the cockpit.
- 你要去哪兒？- 去駕駛艙
The ship is set on autopilot.
船已設置自動駕駛儀
We're in countdown to liftoff.
我們要倒數發射了
No, wait. It's too dangerous. Aki!
等一下 這太危險了 阿琪
Over here, you son of a bitch!
我在這兒 臭怪物
Ryan!
萊恩
Gray, do you read me? What's happening?
葛雷 你收到嗎？怎麼回事？
You and Sid are getting out of here now.
你和席德快走
- No! We can't just leave everyone. - Everyone's dead.
- 不 我不能丟下大家 - 大家都死了
I'm not leaving without you.
我不能丟下你
I'm sorry.
抱歉
But you don't have a choice.
你別無選擇
Goodbye, Aki.
再見 阿琪
Gray, come on!
葛雷 快上來
I just...
我很想…
I wish I could believe they're in a better place.
我很想相信他們到了更好的地方
"宙斯太空站"
"確認目的地 獲准前進"
I enlarged the scanning perimeter
我擴大了搜索範圍
to include an area that we have previously overlooked.
包括了一個之前沒找過的地方
The impact crater.
隕石坑
That's a strange place to find the eighth spirit.
好奇怪的第八個靈魂藏身處
Yes, really. Quite astonishing.
是的 很不可思議
But nothing could survive in there except phantoms.
那兒除了幽怪沒別的生物可以存活下來
Precisely.
沒錯
Which suggests that the eighth spirit is a phantom spirit.
也就是說第八個靈魂是幽怪
I can't explain it at the moment.
我目前不能解釋
- But once we get down there... - Wait!
- 但只要我們下去… - 等一下
- You'll understand... - Wait, doctor.
- 就會明白的… - 慢著 博士
That's a one-way trip.
這可是一去不回
Yes, yes, I expected that's how you would evaluate our chances.
是的 我就知道你是這麼評估我們的機會的
- What, am I wrong? - No, no, no, I agree. We probably
- 我說錯了嗎？- 沒錯 我同意 我們也許
won't live long enough to extract the eighth spirit from the crater.
無法活著把第八個靈魂萃取回來
Then why should we even try it?
那為什麼還要去試？
Because we don't need to extract the eighth spirit.
因為我們不必把第八個靈魂萃取回來
If we can't bring the final spirit here.
如果我們無法找到最後一個靈魂
We can go there and complete the wave inside the crater.
就直接在隕石坑完成能量波
Yes. Exactly.
一點也沒錯
And how do we do that... exactly?
我們該怎麼做？
I can construct a device,
我會設計一個裝置
that would attach to Aki's chest plate to gather the eighth spirit and then...
裝在阿琪身上讓她採集第八個靈魂…
And then what?
然後呢？
And then we wait...
然後就等著瞧…
and see what happens.
會發生什麼事
That's it?
就這祥？
That's your plan? We wait and see what happens?
你的計畫就是等著瞧？
Yes.
沒錯
Oh, good.
太好了
Well I got my own plan.
我也有計劃
We keep scanning the surface from orbit,
繼續從軌道掃描地球表面
and maybe we'll find a compatible spirit somewhere else.
也許能在別處找到相容的第八個靈魂
Aki?
阿琪？
I say we go in.
我建議我們下去
General Hein, you're clear for docking to zero-one-alpha.
海恩將軍 你可連接零一開端
What caused the barrier to fail, General Hein?
海恩將軍 請問防護罩為什麼會失靈？
Ah, I'm afraid it was only a matter of time
這是遲早會發生的事
before the phantoms developed an immunity to our barriers.
幽怪對防護罩產生抵抗力
But I am relieved to see that you and the rest of the Council
但是我很高興看到你和議員們
were able to evacuate to Houston, without incident.
都安全地撤逃到休士頓
It was a terrible loss suffered this evening.
今晚的事件是一場悲劇
The Council had reconsidered your proposal to fire the Zeus cannon.
議會重新考量了你對發射宙斯炮的提議
I see.
很好
We are transmitting the access codes to you now.
我們現在就把發射密碼傳給你
And General...
將軍…
best of luck to us all.
祝大家好運
Prepare to fire the cannon.
準備發射宙斯炮
The target, sir?
目標是？
The phantom crater.
幽怪隕石坑
"裡海山脈 幽怪隕石坑"
Preparing to drop in three, two, one.
準備降落 3 2 l
Powering the shield.
啟動防護罩
Okay, we are over the meteor.
我們在隕石坑上方
Do you have it in sight, doctor?
你看到了嗎 博士？
There are so many of them.
有太多幽怪了
Wait.
等等
Yes!
是的
I'm tracking the eighth spirit moving along the crater's surface.
我追蹤到在隕石坑表面的第八個靈魂
All right. Now let's take a closer look.
好 那就靠近一點
Ready to fire in three minutes.
準備三分鐘後發射
OVO-packs at maximum.
開到最強電力
Transferring plasma flow to auto.
轉換自動流量
Counter-thrusters are engaged.
反制推動器準備好了
Lox flow de-coupled.
開啟流管鎖
Status is green.
一切正常
We have something on the radar over the impact site, sir.
我們發現隕石坑有動靜
It's her.
是她
Sir?
長官？
Just a traitor under the influence of the enemy.
是被敵人控制的叛徒
Continue the countdown.
繼續倒數計時
We'll take them all out at the same time.
我們一起把它們消滅掉
We're closing on the phantom. Contact in 30 seconds.
接近幽怪了 三十秒後接觸
Target locked.
目標鎖定
Ready to fire on your command.
等待你下令發射
It's a match. It's a perfect match.
完全符合 能量波完全符合
- Target scanners ready, sir. - Fire!
- 準備好了 - 發射
What was that?
那是什麼？
It's the Zeus. They're firing on the crater.
是宙斯炮 他們向隕石坑發射宙斯炮
Aki, Captain, are you all right?
你們沒事吧？
A little shaken. Stand by.
只是嚇了一跳 請待命
Sid, the eighth spirit is not on our scanner. Do you have it?
我在掃描器上看不到第八個靈魂 你看得到嗎？
The eighth spirit...
第八個靈魂…
has been destroyed.
被消滅了
What are we going to do now?
現在該怎麼辦？
Nothing. This mission is over.
沒怎麼辦 任務結束了
- We have to get out of here. - Incoming!
- 我們要離開這 - 襲擊來了
What is that?
那是什麼？
If you're gonna get us out of here, you better do it now.
我們要走就得趁現在
Hold on!
堅持住
I can't hold on to you.
我堅持不住了
Unable to maintain altitude...
無法維持高度…
Emergency landing procedures.
啟動緊急降落程式
Come in. Come in, please.
快回答我
Aki, Gray, can you hear me?
阿琪 葛雷 你們收到了嗎？
Sid, I need to talk to the station.
博士 我要和他們對話
Can you patch us through?
你能幫我接去太空站嗎？
What is that thing?
那是什麼東西？
I don't know, sir.
我不知道 長官
Incoming message, sir.
有資訊傳送進來 長官
General Hein, you must cease fire immediately.
海恩將軍 請你立刻停火
What you're looking at in the crater is the living spirit of an alien's home world.
你所看到的是外星人的地靈
The planet was destroyed and part of it landed here.
它們的星球被毀滅後降落到地球
This is not an invasion. It never was.
這從一開始就不是侵略行動
Oh, I see.
原來如此
And... and what we have been fighting all this time, doctor? Ghosts?
那我們都在跟什麼打仗？鬼魂嗎？
Yes,
沒錯
spirits that are confused, lost and angry.
感到迷惑 失落和憤怒的鬼魂
Oh, right? And these spirits are coming out of this Gaia thing
是嗎？這些鬼都是來自蓋亞
General Hein, you have to listen...
將軍 你要聽我說…
Alien Gaia, Earth Gaia...
外星蓋亞 地球蓋亞…
Doctor, even if I believed in such nonsense,
就算我相信這些
the fact remains the Earth is under attack
地球仍然受到侵略者的攻擊
from an aggressor who must be destroyed at all costs.
它們必須被不擇手段的消滅掉
The cost may be the entire planet, sir.
代價是地球也會被毀滅
Firing on the alien Gaia will only make it stronger.
外星蓋亞遭到攻擊後會更強大
Well, since you're under the alien's influence, doctor...
既然你是受到外星人的影響
I will take your protest to mean that,
我會接受你的提議
we are in fact pursuing the correct course of action. So,
我們會採取正確的行動 所以…
I suggest you take your last few moments
我建議你珍惜最後的時光
and prepare to meet your Gaia.
等著去見你的蓋亞吧
Continue to fire until the invader has been destroyed.
繼續開火直到完全殲滅侵略者
General, the system is overheating, sir.
將軍 系統過熱了
We are going to hit again and again...
我要不斷的攻擊…
and keep on hitting it, until it's dead.
直到它們全死光
But sir, we're not even sure if it's having any effect on the creature.
我們不確定這是不是有沒有效
No effect?
有沒有效？
We've got them on the run, soldier.
它們已經走投無路了
This is our moment of victory.
勝利就快來臨
I order you to fire.
我命令你發射
- The system won't allow us to fire again. - We'll see about that.
- 系統無法繼續發射 - 等著瞧吧
Our shield is out. We're sitting ducks in here. Come on.
防護罩失效 這是等死了
This is not a good place to be.
這不是個可以留下的好地方
What the hell is that?
那是什麼東西？
- That's not what I think it is, is it? - Yes! It's Gaia.
- 和我想像的一樣嗎？- 是 這就是蓋亞
This is definitely not a good place to be.
這的確不是個可以留下的好地方
- Hey, are you all right? - I'm fine.
- 你沒事吧？- 沒事
I have to talk to Dr. Sid.
我得跟席德博士通話
Sid, do you read me?
席德 你收到了嗎？
Go ahead. I'm still here.
我還在 說吧
We're looking at Gaia. Do you hear me, Sid? Gaia!
蓋亞就在我們眼前 聽到了嗎？蓋亞
I... I think this explains why the eighth spirit appeared here.
這解釋了為什麼第八個靈魂會在這裡
Yes.
沒錯
Yes, that's it.
沒錯 這就對了
A phantom must have changed into the eighth spirit
一隻幽怪接觸到我們蓋亞產生的生命
when it touched a new life born from our own Gaia.
於是它轉變成第八個靈魂
If so, it would have been given a different energy signature
所以它的能量波
that set it apart from the other phantoms.
才會跟別的幽怪不同
Ah, you two could not have hoped
這是找到新而相容
for a better location to find a new compatible spirit.
第八個靈魂的最佳地點
Whatever you do, don't move.
無論如何都不要動
Stay right where you are.
留在原地
Staying right where we are may not be as easy as it sounds.
留在這裡可不像聽上去那麼容易
Don't shoot any of them.
別對它們任何一個開槍
You could very well destroy our last hope.
你很可能會毀掉我們最後一線希望
And what do you suggest I do, Doctor?
你要讓我怎樣？
Ask them to play nice?
叫它們乖一點嗎？
Combat strategy is your area of expertise, captain, not mine.
戰略是你的專長 隊長 不是我的
I have a reading here in the fissure, Do you see it?
我在裂口這裡收到了能量波 你看到了嗎？
Yes, a compatible spirit.
是的 那是相容的第八個靈魂
It must be very near you.
它一定離你很近
Well, which one is it?
那麼 哪一個才是？
Which one?
哪一個？
I'm having difficulty narrowing it down, just a moment please.
我還看不出來 請等一下
Doctor, it's getting crowded in here. Aki, we don't have much time.
這裡變得太擠了 阿琪 沒有時間了
Aki... Aki!
阿琪… 阿琪
With the hope of new life,
抱著新生命的希望
has Gaia changed the phantom within?
蓋亞改變了內在的幽怪嗎？
I have it.
我找到了
Gray, get in here. I need you.
快進來 我需要你
Do you hear me, Sid?
你聽到了嗎 席德？
The wave pattern is complete.
能量波完成了
Yes, I read you. This is wonderful.
收到了 真是太好了
I don't see how you could have found the final spirit.
我不知道你怎樣找到了最後一個靈魂
It found me, doctor.
是它找到了我
Oh, my word.
我的天
I see now...
我知道了…
I understand.
我懂了
Well I don't understand. What the hell is going on?
我不懂 到底是怎麼回事？
Give me your OVO-pack. I need to project the completed wave.
給我你的電池 我需要它來完成發射能量波
- But we'll be defenseless. - Just do it.
- 我們會變得手無寸鐵 - 你照做吧
I hope you know what you're doing, Aki.
我希望你們知道在幹嘛
- We can use the shield to project the wave. - What?
- 我們要用防護罩發射能量波 - 什麼？
Dr. Sid's theory was right. I have it, the eighth spirit.
席德博士說得對 我已得到了第八個靈魂
I'm cured, Gray.
我痊癒了 葛雷
Are you sure you have the final spirit?
你確定你得到了最後一個靈魂？
Yes, yes. I'm sure.
我很確定
But how? How can you know that?
你怎麼知道？
Don't worry, a phantom told me.
別擔心 一隻幽怪告訴我的
Oh, great.
是嗎 太好了
That's it. Shield on.
好了 啟動防護罩
It's not working. We have to do something before it's too late.
沒有用 我們要趕快想辦法
If this doesn't work, then it's already too late.
這若是沒用的話 一切都太遲了
Gray... trust me.
相信我
I'll blast you all to hell.
我要把你們都打下地獄
No! No!
不
Get down!
趴下來
"警告 系統超載"
I know.
我知道
"警告 系統超載"
I know!
我知道了
But it must be done.
但一定要這樣
Fire!
發射
Fire, damn you!
發射 快呀
Fire!
發射
Gray?
葛雷？
Don't leave me, Gray.
別丟下我 葛雷
I told Sid this was a one-way trip.
我告訴博士這次是有去無回了
Looks like I was right.
看來我說對了
No, Gray. Hang on, please.
不 你要撐下去
I still have the wave.
我仍有能量波
We can get through this.
我們撐的過去的
- We're not gonna make it. - We're going to make it.
- 來不及了 - 來得及
We both know that isn't true.
我們都知道來不及了
Gray...
葛雷…
Help me.
扶我起來
Gray...
葛雷…
Listen to me.
聽我說
You saved my life once.
你救過我
Now I want you to save yourself. Gray,
現在我要你救自己 葛雷
no. Please.
不 求你了？
Let me do this, Aki. Trust me.
讓我這麼做 阿琪 相信我
Don't leave me, Gray.
葛雷 別離開我
You've been trying to tell me that death isn't the end.
你一直說死亡並不是終結
Don't back out on me.
在我終於相信後
Now that I finally believe.
別說不是
I love you.
我愛你
Oh, it's warm.
哦 好暖和啊
∮ free ∮
∮ the dream within ∮
∮ the stars are crying ∮
∮ a tear ∮
∮ a sigh ∮
∮ escapes from heaven ∮
∮ and worlds end ∮
∮ breathe ∮
∮ the dream within ∮
∮ the mystifying ∮
∮ we tremble and spin ∮
∮ suspended within ∮
∮ look beyond ∮
∮ where hearts can see ∮
∮ dream in peace ∮
∮ trust the belief ∮
∮ we tremble and spin ∮
∮ suspended within ∮
∮ free ∮
∮ the dream within ∮
∮ the voice is calling ∮
∮ a song ∮
∮ a prayer ∮
∮ from deep inside you ∮
∮ to guide you ∮
∮ be ∮
∮ the dream within ∮
∮ the light is shining ∮
∮ a flight on the wind ∮
∮ salvation begins ∮
∮ look beyond ∮
∮ where hearts can see ∮
∮ dream in peace ∮
∮ trust the belief ∮
∮ we tremble and spin ∮
∮ suspended within ∮
∮ free ∮
∮ the dream within ∮
∮ the stars are crying ∮
∮ a tear ∮
∮ a sigh ∮
∮ escapes from heaven ∮
∮ and worlds end ∮